

ABOUT ME

Hello there, my name is Tareq and I am a frontend Engineer who is driven by passion and the will to learn towards Web Development. I have achieved and succeded in changing my career path from a Linguest to a developer, yes that's right, I have dived into the code, into the bits and pieces of frontend development until I kickstarted the inner developer of me.

I have a good experience throughout the companies I worked in, from doing basic HTML pages, to making single page JS applications where performence is a must.

CONTACT ME

- □ tareqhassan54@gmail.com
- +962 790 99 61 87
- (S) tareqhassan90
- Amman, Jordan
- Married

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Excellent reading, writing and speaking.

English

Excellent reading, writing and speaking.

INTERESTS



Gaming



月 Music





Cooking

TAREQ HASSAN

Frontend Engineer



EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer at Souq.com | Jordan

Aug 2015 - Present

- Leading a group of 5 People.
- Maintaining Souq.com Frontend Application.
- Developing a cross-platform (SCSS) framework built on top of Zurb Foundation.
- Developing ECMAScript 6 Class Based, design patterned JavaScript modules along side with functional programming Libraries such as UnderscoreJS.
- Applying ECMAScript 6 new features in the code.
- Writing Automated Scripts using Grunt & Gulp for Development and Production environment .
- Doing JS Profiling to maintain a high speed low profile state for the site.
- Enriching the UX of Souq.com Frontend Application.
- Stack of technologies: Foundation SCSS, RequireJS ECMAScript 6, BabelJS, Foundation 6, Grunt & Gulp.

Software Engineer at Rocket Internet SE | Germany

April 2015 - Aug 2015 (5 months)

- Developing Cross compatible sites, JavaScript Oriented sites.
- Worked for a startup called EverJobs: http://everjobs.com

Frontend Engineer at iHorizons | Jordan

May 2014 - March 2015 (11 months)

- Mainly Integrating Static PSDs Into a Dynamic , and W3C validated site Using .NET and MVC4 Framework.
- Integrating JavaScript to convey various functionality for the user.
- Maintaining Cross-browsers compatibly.
- Developing JavaScript Plugins.

Magento Frontend Engineer at ShopGo | Jordan

Oct 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 8 months)

- Developing High end Magento Themes PSD Slicing Using CSS and HTML, in Addition to Animation using CSS3.
- Developing Basic Magento Extension Using Magento Zend/PHP, and ¡Query/Javascript.
- Took the lead of any Customization Clients.
- Maintain Themes on Monthly basis.
- Maintain Cross-compatibly for all themes.
- Solving Tickets for Clients.

EDUCATION

Jordan University of Science & Technology

2008 - 2011

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Applied English and Linguistics, Grade: 78.7



CERTIFICATIONS

Magento Frontend Developer Certification (MFDC)

December 2014

Magento License z9flon5022



SKILLS

ECMAScript Mustache.js | jQuery | JIRA | Git | CSS | E-commerce | LESS | Handlebars.js PHP

JavaScript Web Design HTML5 Facebook API

Responsive Design

Zurb Foundation Underscore.js

Bootstrap Responsive Design CSS3 Animation Compass GruntJS Gulp.js